## TARA HENLEY

4848 Hatcher St 3003 ● Dallas, Texas 75210 ● 469-335-7401 ● tara.henley.th@gmail.com

#### CERTIFIED NURSING ASSISTANT

#### Objective

Reliable, service-focused nursing professional with excellent patient-care and charting skills gained through ten years of experience as a CNA. Compassionate and technically skilled in attending to patients in diverse healthcare settings. BLS and CPR certified (current).

#### Skills

- Patient Care & Safety
- Diagnostic Testing
- Medical Terminology
- Electronic Medical Records
- Vital Signs & Patient Monitoring
- Medication Administration
- Privacy / HIPAA Regulations
- Patient Advocacy and Support

## **Work Experience**

# Patient Care Technician OPTIMAL HOME HEALTH

November 2016-2017 Dallas, Tx

- Develop and maintain patient care plans as assigned by Registered Nurse in Charge
- Report all patients related Activity to Senior Management in a timely manner
- Take and Record patient blood pressure, pulse rate, weight, temperature, Respiration rate
- Maintain the Safety of patients inspect and clean work area help with toileting

#### PATIENT CARE TECHNICAN / PHLEBOTOMY

#### METHODIST DALLAS MEDICAL CENTER

• Answer patient call lights, determine patients needs.

November 2014-January 2015

Dallas,TX

• Draw Patients lab Blood work ,turn or reposition bedridden patients.

Patient Care Technician May 2014 - October 2014

## UNIVERSITY GENERAL HOSPITAL

Dallas, TX

- Answer patient call signals, signal lights, bells, or intercom systems to determine patients' needs.
- Turn or reposition bedridden patients.
- Provide physical support to assist patients to perform daily living activities, such as getting out of bed, bathing, dressing, using the toilet, and standing, walking, or exercising.
- Review patients' dietary restrictions, food allergies, and preferences to ensure patient receives appropriate diet.

#### CERTIFIED NURSING ASSISTANT

April 2010 - November 2012

## DALLAS CENTER OF REHAB

Dallas, TX

- Measured and recorded food and liquid intake or urinary and fecal output, reporting changes to medical or nursing staff.
- Recorded vital signs, such as temperature, blood pressure, pulse, or respiration rate, as directed by medical or nursing staff.
- Gathered information from caregivers, nurses, or physicians about patient condition, treatment plans, or appropriate activities.
- Observed or examined patients to detect symptoms that may require medical attention, such as bruises, open wounds, or blood in urine.

## CERTIFIED NURSING ASSISTANT

June 2006 - December 2009

CRESTVIEW COURT Dallas, TX

- Documented or otherwise reported observations of patient behavior, complaints, or physical symptoms to nurses.
- Reminded patients to take medications or nutritional supplements.
- Answered patient call signals, signal lights, bells, or intercom systems to determine patients' needs.

• Turned or repositioned bedridden patients.

Patient Care Associate March 2000 - March 2005

### A ONE PLUS HOME HEALTH

Duncanville, TX

- Provided high-quality patient care as an in-demand per-diem CNA within surgical, acute-care, rehabilitation, home-healthcare and nursing-home settings.
- Preserved patient dignity and minimize discomfort while carrying out duties such as bedpan changes, diapering, emptying drainage bags and bathing.
- Commended for chart accuracy, effective team collaboration, patient relations and consistent delivery of empathetic care.

## **Education**

**D**IPLOMA 1989

HILLCREST HIGH SCHOOL Dallas, TX

Certification - Nurse Aide February 2006

GIDEON SERVICES Dallas, TX